<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Roy Xue is Here :)</title>
    <description>Roy,Lijun,Xue,Roy Xue,Lijun Xue,薛立君</description>
    <link>http://royxue.me/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://royxue.me/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2015 17:15:10 +0900</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 May 2015 17:15:10 +0900</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Blog: Naive</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Too Naive&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2015 09:30:46 +0900</pubDate>
        <link>http://royxue.me/blog/naive</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://royxue.me/blog/naive</guid>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Blog: Never Better, Never Worse</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;东京是很好的城市, 只是有时候太拥挤了, 当你心情烦躁的时候, 很难找到一个地方坐下休息一会, 喘口气. 偶尔开始怀念广州的那间麦当劳和那个落地玻璃前面的位子, 至少是个发呆的好地方.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;遇见了很好的姑娘, 却隔着一片海, 因为签证的关系想回去看她却回不去. 她忘记关Skype的那个晚上, 隔着耳机, 传来她均匀的呼吸声, 突然就睡不着了. 只想享受这个美妙的时刻. 不记得是几点睡着了, 只是记得那个晚上想了很多, 关于现在, 关于未来, 关于安全感. 和那一份想要好好对待她的心情. 有很多的事情, 如果我现在可以做到, 几年后我一样可以做到, 可是如果错过了她的话, 就不会再有第二次机会了. 果然我只是一个喜欢一期一会这个词, 却不会愿意这么做的人. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;不知道为什么前一个晚上突然有很多人找我一起聊人生和理想. 自己好像变成了一个没什么远大理想的人. 就好比来日本, 只是因为想见こじはる. 没有太怎么花心思去描绘未来, 也没怎么想过未来的自己会是什么样子. 也许吧, 我想过的生活很简单, 和喜欢的姑娘做好玩的事情就足够了. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;等待是一种很复杂的心情, 尤其是面对着那些不确定的事情. 所以如果不用考虑那么多事情该多好. 大概只是难以思考或者不想去思考未来的形状, 走一步看一步未必是一件坏事, 只是有些时候会手足无措. 最近, 身边的同事开始问喜不喜欢日本, 要不要留在日本继续工作, 却难以决定.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;不管怎么样, 至少现在开心就好 :)&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2015 17:08:11 +0900</pubDate>
        <link>http://royxue.me/blog/life/never-better-never-worse</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://royxue.me/blog/life/never-better-never-worse</guid>
        
        <category>随笔</category>
        
        <category>Lalala</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
        <category>life</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Blog: 好照片</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;今天出门了一天, 拍了些照片.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;突然很想问自己一个问题, 什么样的照片才是好照片.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;我想，要拍出好看的照片应该是一件不太难的事情, 选好角度调好参数, 实在不行后期再用PS处理一下, 就有了好看的照片. 这一类的照片在500px上比比皆是. 可是仅仅好看就够了吗?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;我想并不是这样, 如果仅仅是好看的话, 看过之后很快就忘记了. 但是我觉得好的照片应该是能够被记住的. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;照片记录了一个瞬间, 可是这一个瞬间却对应着一段回忆. 所以我想大概好的照片应该拥有它背后的故事. 就好像今天, 在浅草寺遇到的老爷爷和狗, 如果只是一张单纯的照片只会觉得狗很可爱, 可是在画面之外的地方, 这只狗已经十四岁了, 和老爷爷一样进入暮年, 才能明白他们对视的时候眼中流露的那些感情. 也许是携手一起度过最后一段人生的珍惜.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;我想这就是我所认为的好照片, 也是我想拍出来的照片.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;我想用照片来讲故事给你听.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 18 Apr 2015 22:45:35 +0900</pubDate>
        <link>http://royxue.me/blog/life/good-photo</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://royxue.me/blog/life/good-photo</guid>
        
        <category>Photography</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
        <category>life</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Blog: Build Minecraft Server on DigitalOcean</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Hmmmm, since last time I killed the XXX dragon I havent play Minecraft for a long time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So this time, I think it would be nice to play multi-players game, I wanna enjoy this game once more with lovely Sarah :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing is to build a minecraft server. I choose DigitalOcean VPS, just because there are some money left there and the speed is not bad ;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So the first step is create a droplet in digitalocean, it’s pretty easy, $5/month one should work well for 2 playes(max would be 6 or 7 I think), if more, just choose a more expensive one. Then use ssh to connect your server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cause Minecraft is based on Java, so the first thing we must do is install Java in the droplet, because we wont use any GUI related, so we only install default-jre-headless is enough, in which headless means lack of any GUI libraries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;apt-get install default-jre-headless
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next create it a folder to store the minecraft .jar file, and also create a group and user to own the minecraft Java process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;mkdir /srv/minecraft  
addgroup --system minecraft  
adduser --system --no-create-home --home /srv/minecraft --ingroup minecraft minecraft  
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then lets install minecraft&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;cd /srv/minecraft  
wget https://s3.amazonaws.com/Minecraft.Download/versions/1.8/minecraft_server.1.8.jar -O minecraft_server.jar  
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After install the minecraft game, we can start the server by&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;java -Xms32M -Xmx450M -jar minecraft_server.jar nogui
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The two parameters mean we start the process with 32M RAM and the max limit would be 450M(cause we only have 512M). However, this is the first time we ran the server, so it wont work well until we agree the EULA(End-User License Agreement), so you stop the server first, and find the eula.txt file under minecraft folder, change the value from false to true.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This time restart the server, it would work well, and some new files would appear like banned-players.json, banned-ips.json, ops.json, and whitelist.json, if you need these functions, just modify it into what you want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the way, for a server we cannot just keep minecraft in commend line, we need to create a script make minecraft run as a service, first, create the configuration by running:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;vi /etc/init/minecraft.conf  
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And set the contents&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;# description &quot;start and stop the minecraft-server&quot;

start on runlevel [2345]  
stop on runlevel [^2345]

console log  
chdir /srv/minecraft  
setuid minecraft  
setgid minecraft

respawn  
respawn limit 20 5

exec /usr/bin/java -Xms32M -Xmx450M -jar minecraft_server.jar nogui  
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;then lets create a symlink under /etc/init.d by running:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;ln -s /etc/init/minecraft.conf /etc/init.d/minecraft  
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Set the folder owned to minecraft&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;chown -R minecraft:minecraft /srv/minecraft  
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ok, after this step you can easily manage your minecraft server by &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;service minecraft start  
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lalala, till now, all things have been done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Open your minecraft, connect to IP:25565 to enjoy your game :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2015 00:59:15 +0900</pubDate>
        <link>http://royxue.me/blog/dev/fun/build-minecraft-server-on-digitalocean</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://royxue.me/blog/dev/fun/build-minecraft-server-on-digitalocean</guid>
        
        <category>Minecraft</category>
        
        <category>DigitalOcean</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
        <category>dev</category>
        
        <category>fun</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>: iOS Facebook Login with Swift</title>
        <description>
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2015 18:47:19 +0900</pubDate>
        <link>http://royxue.me/ios-facebook-login-with-swift</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://royxue.me/ios-facebook-login-with-swift</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Blog: First Time Icon Design</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://royxue.me/assets/img/blog/icon_design.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hey, this is my first design work. hmmmm, it’s a kinda simple calendar app icon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been interested in design for a long time. But just dont have enough time to learn how. So this week I have one free afternoon time to try some design work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tools I use is Sketch 3.0 trial version. hmmm, it’s a powerful tools, much easier than Photoshop, maybe the only thing I need is a better mouse haha.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the process, I think the most difficult part should be how to think about a good idea. Thats what a good design needed. At first, I think maybe calendar icon should be easy, cause most of this kind icons looks similar. However, after finish the main framework, it’s very ugly, and there should be something to make it special.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I turned to Dribbble to find some ideas, then I made one pretty similar as Fantastical icon, that icon looks pretty good. At the end, I thought this is my first time do design work, why not make a self-design one, so after long time thinking, I decided to make this label icon one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Design is complex work, which you should put lots of time on details and design ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 12 Apr 2015 23:02:43 +0900</pubDate>
        <link>http://royxue.me/blog/design/first-time-icon-design</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://royxue.me/blog/design/first-time-icon-design</guid>
        
        <category>design</category>
        
        <category>icon</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
        <category>design</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Blog: Loading Rails Models into FullCalendar</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://fullcalendar.io/&quot;&gt;Fullcalendar&lt;/a&gt; is a powerful javascript calendar. It would be convenient if u wanna build some calendar-based service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using Fullcalendar is not very complex. First, u need to install FullCalendar in your Rails app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;gem &#39;fullcalendar-rails&#39;
gem &#39;moment-rails&#39;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and add following lines to your js&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;//= require moment
//= require fullcalendar and css files

*= require fullcalendar
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The basic usage is very easy, put &lt;em&gt;“&amp;lt;div class=&quot;calendar&quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/dic&amp;gt;“&lt;/em&gt;  in html, and put following code in to coffee files(or put js version in js)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ -&amp;gt;
  		$(document).ready -&amp;gt;
		$(&#39;#calendar&#39;).fullCalendar {
		      header: {
		        left: &#39;prev,next today&#39;,
		        center: &#39;title&#39;,
		        right: &#39;month,agendaWeek,agendaDay&#39;
		      },
		      monthNames: [&quot;一月&quot;, &quot;二月&quot;, &quot;三月&quot;, &quot;四月&quot;, &quot;五月&quot;, &quot;六月&quot;, &quot;七月&quot;, &quot;八月&quot;, &quot;九月&quot;, &quot;十月&quot;, &quot;十一月&quot;, &quot;十二月&quot;],
		      monthNamesShort: [&quot;一月&quot;, &quot;二月&quot;, &quot;三月&quot;, &quot;四月&quot;, &quot;五月&quot;, &quot;六月&quot;, &quot;七月&quot;, &quot;八月&quot;, &quot;九月&quot;, &quot;十月&quot;, &quot;十一月&quot;, &quot;十二月&quot;],
		      dayNames: [&quot;日曜日&quot;, &quot;月曜日&quot;, &quot;火曜日&quot;, &quot;水曜日&quot;, &quot;木曜日&quot;, &quot;金曜日&quot;, &quot;土曜日&quot;],
		      dayNamesShort: [&quot;日曜日&quot;, &quot;月曜日&quot;, &quot;火曜日&quot;, &quot;水曜日&quot;, &quot;木曜日&quot;, &quot;金曜日&quot;, &quot;土曜日&quot;],  
		    }
	    return
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;FullCalendar uses EventObject to load events data and show on the calendar, EventObject is json format data loaded in js files, so here we need to load our Model data into FullCalendar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here I will how to load events in users views(a little more difficult than load in events views)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, in models/event.rb, add&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;  def as_json(options = {})
	{
      :id =&amp;gt; self.id,
      :title =&amp;gt; self.name,
      :start =&amp;gt; self.start_time,
      :end =&amp;gt; self.end_time,
      :description =&amp;gt; self.description,
      :allDay =&amp;gt; self.is_all_day,
 	 }
 	 end
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here the code will tranfer event data in to json format, id, title, start, end, allDay is important, make sure in your model have these datas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then in controller/users_controller.rb&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;  respond_to do |format|
    format.html
    format.json { render json:@events.to_json }
  end
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;render the @events objects into json format, so now this json url should be like localhost:3000/users/(:id).json&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The final step is to load json in js&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;events: window.location.href + &#39;.json&#39;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Use window.location.href to get current url, plus “.json”, hmmm, it’s a lazy way haha.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Till now, the FullCalendar would work for you :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2015 18:57:23 +0900</pubDate>
        <link>http://royxue.me/blog/dev/rails/loading-rails-models-into-fullcalendar</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://royxue.me/blog/dev/rails/loading-rails-models-into-fullcalendar</guid>
        
        <category>Rails</category>
        
        <category>ruby</category>
        
        <category>fullcalendar</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
        <category>dev</category>
        
        <category>rails</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Blog: Bookmarks Migration Plan</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been using Chrome bookmarks for a long time, the folder stucture gradually become deep and messy, so I think it’s time to change!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At first, what I wanna do is to find a designed Mac OS app to manage all bookmarks offline, but unfortuantely I didnt find satisfied one, good design and reasonable price app is hard to find, whatever if you dont mind price, &lt;a href=&quot;fetching.io&quot;&gt;fetching&lt;/a&gt; is a good one. &lt;a href=&quot;raindrop.io&quot;&gt;RainDrop&lt;/a&gt; is also good, but hmmm… it’s just too many bugs inside this Beta version, even I cannot import my bookmarks, but as it will getting better, so I would use it when it can work well in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I turned to online bookmarks service, honestly pinboard is the best choice, but after it’s change to per-year price, it would be a little hard to accept that. Finally, I decide to use &lt;a href=&quot;https://delicious.com&quot;&gt;Delicious&lt;/a&gt;. It’s free but some ads there. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, a good app is needed for better experience, I use Shiori now, it’s light but beatiful, u can set the hot key to easily store and open the bookmarks.(like another Alfred, haha) &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://royxue.me/assets/img/blog/shiori.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hmmmm, I think maybe Im not going to import Chrome bookmarks into Delicous, but use Delicious as new service for storing bookmarks, Chrome bookmarks only for those website I always use in daily life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If u r interested, just follow &lt;a href=&quot;https://delicious.com/royxue&quot;&gt;me&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2015 11:29:01 +0900</pubDate>
        <link>http://royxue.me/blog/life/dev/bookmarks-migration-plan</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://royxue.me/blog/life/dev/bookmarks-migration-plan</guid>
        
        <category>bookmarks</category>
        
        <category>Mac OSX</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
        <category>life</category>
        
        <category>dev</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Dev: Start From Here</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The title is just a little bit weired, where is here? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to Kakazu San give my this oppotunity to do my own project in one month. This Monday, I shared my ideas in company meeting, and finally decide what to do in the following one month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The moment I decided the idea make me remind of 4 months ago in the Hackathon. Team always make things easier, but this time I can only do it by myself, which means building back end, front end, and design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it’s a good chance to try something cool! &lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2015 01:54:11 +0900</pubDate>
        <link>http://royxue.me/dev/start-from-here</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://royxue.me/dev/start-from-here</guid>
        
        <category>Japanese</category>
        
        <category>Rails</category>
        
        
        <category>dev</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Blog: Living in Japan</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Now it’s my third week in Japan. Life is just too busy to catch up all stuffs, like writing this blog :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whatever, I love this city, this country. Always I feel like that I am like a new delivered baby, so eager to see, to experience the this new world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I learnt Rails in previous 2 weeks, finished some web development tasks by Rails. I guess the actual time spending on learning Rails maybe less than one week? Im just not sure about it. But, Python and Ruby, Django and Rails are pretty similar except the grammar difference. The previous Django and Python knowledge helped me a lot on Ruby. Ruby is kind of language you can write like a poem, which means one beautiful line to do something powerful, hmmm, this is what I wanna learn more in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guest the most important things on my wish list have been finished, saw kojiharu in the real life is the best moment in Japan till now. It’s a little bit difficult to describe the feeling at that moment. doki doki doki doki. haha.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next week, I will start my own project, although till now I have no idea about what to do. Im looking forward to the first step, because there are lots of things to learn, to try, to enjoy!~~~&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2015 18:36:40 +0900</pubDate>
        <link>http://royxue.me/blog/life/living-in-japan</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://royxue.me/blog/life/living-in-japan</guid>
        
        <category>travel</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
        <category>life</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
