<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Roy Xue is Here :)</title>
    <description>Roy,Lijun,Xue,Roy Xue,Lijun Xue,薛立君</description>
    <link>http://royxue.me/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://royxue.me/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Sun, 12 Apr 2015 23:23:51 +0900</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Apr 2015 23:23:51 +0900</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Blog: First Time Icon Design</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://royxue.me/assets/img/blog/icon_design.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hey, this is my first design work. hmmmm, it’s a kinda simple calendar app icon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been interested in design for a long time. But just dont have enough time to learn how. So this week I have one free afternoon time to try some design work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tools I use is Sketch 3.0 trial version. hmmm, it’s a powerful tools, much easier than Photoshop, maybe the only thing I need is a better mouse haha.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the process, I think the most difficult part should be how to think about a good idea. Thats what a good design needed. At first, I think maybe calendar icon should be easy, cause most of this kind icons looks similar. However, after finish the main framework, it’s very ugly, and there should be something to make it special.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I turned to Dribbble to find some ideas, then I made one pretty similar as Fantastical icon, that icon looks pretty good. At the end, I thought this is my first time do design work, why not make a self-design one, so after long time thinking, I decided to make this label icon one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Design is complex work, which you should put lots of time on details and design ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 12 Apr 2015 23:02:43 +0900</pubDate>
        <link>http://royxue.me/blog/design/first-time-icon-design</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://royxue.me/blog/design/first-time-icon-design</guid>
        
        <category>design</category>
        
        <category>icon</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
        <category>design</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Blog: Loading Rails Models into FullCalendar</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://fullcalendar.io/&quot;&gt;Fullcalendar&lt;/a&gt; is a powerful javascript calendar. It would be convenient if u wanna build some calendar-based service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using Fullcalendar is not very complex. First, u need to install FullCalendar in your Rails app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;gem &#39;fullcalendar-rails&#39;
gem &#39;moment-rails&#39;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and add following lines to your js&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;//= require moment
//= require fullcalendar and css files

*= require fullcalendar
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The basic usage is very easy, put &lt;em&gt;“&amp;lt;div class=&quot;calendar&quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/dic&amp;gt;“&lt;/em&gt;  in html, and put following code in to coffee files(or put js version in js)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ -&amp;gt;
  		$(document).ready -&amp;gt;
		$(&#39;#calendar&#39;).fullCalendar {
		      header: {
		        left: &#39;prev,next today&#39;,
		        center: &#39;title&#39;,
		        right: &#39;month,agendaWeek,agendaDay&#39;
		      },
		      monthNames: [&quot;一月&quot;, &quot;二月&quot;, &quot;三月&quot;, &quot;四月&quot;, &quot;五月&quot;, &quot;六月&quot;, &quot;七月&quot;, &quot;八月&quot;, &quot;九月&quot;, &quot;十月&quot;, &quot;十一月&quot;, &quot;十二月&quot;],
		      monthNamesShort: [&quot;一月&quot;, &quot;二月&quot;, &quot;三月&quot;, &quot;四月&quot;, &quot;五月&quot;, &quot;六月&quot;, &quot;七月&quot;, &quot;八月&quot;, &quot;九月&quot;, &quot;十月&quot;, &quot;十一月&quot;, &quot;十二月&quot;],
		      dayNames: [&quot;日曜日&quot;, &quot;月曜日&quot;, &quot;火曜日&quot;, &quot;水曜日&quot;, &quot;木曜日&quot;, &quot;金曜日&quot;, &quot;土曜日&quot;],
		      dayNamesShort: [&quot;日曜日&quot;, &quot;月曜日&quot;, &quot;火曜日&quot;, &quot;水曜日&quot;, &quot;木曜日&quot;, &quot;金曜日&quot;, &quot;土曜日&quot;],  
		    }
	    return
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;FullCalendar uses EventObject to load events data and show on the calendar, EventObject is json format data loaded in js files, so here we need to load our Model data into FullCalendar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here I will how to load events in users views(a little more difficult than load in events views)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, in models/event.rb, add&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;  def as_json(options = {})
	{
      :id =&amp;gt; self.id,
      :title =&amp;gt; self.name,
      :start =&amp;gt; self.start_time,
      :end =&amp;gt; self.end_time,
      :description =&amp;gt; self.description,
      :allDay =&amp;gt; self.is_all_day,
 	 }
 	 end
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here the code will tranfer event data in to json format, id, title, start, end, allDay is important, make sure in your model have these datas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then in controller/users_controller.rb&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;  respond_to do |format|
    format.html
    format.json { render json:@events.to_json }
  end
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;render the @events objects into json format, so now this json url should be like localhost:3000/users/(:id).json&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The final step is to load json in js&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;events: window.location.href + &#39;.json&#39;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Use window.location.href to get current url, plus “.json”, hmmm, it’s a lazy way haha.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Till now, the FullCalendar would work for you :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2015 18:57:23 +0900</pubDate>
        <link>http://royxue.me/blog/dev/rails/loading-rails-models-into-fullcalendar</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://royxue.me/blog/dev/rails/loading-rails-models-into-fullcalendar</guid>
        
        <category>Rails</category>
        
        <category>ruby</category>
        
        <category>fullcalendar</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
        <category>dev</category>
        
        <category>rails</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Blog: Bookmarks Migration Plan</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been using Chrome bookmarks for a long time, the folder stucture gradually become deep and messy, so I think it’s time to change!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At first, what I wanna do is to find a designed Mac OS app to manage all bookmarks offline, but unfortuantely I didnt find satisfied one, good design and reasonable price app is hard to find, whatever if you dont mind price, &lt;a href=&quot;fetching.io&quot;&gt;fetching&lt;/a&gt; is a good one. &lt;a href=&quot;raindrop.io&quot;&gt;RainDrop&lt;/a&gt; is also good, but hmmm… it’s just too many bugs inside this Beta version, even I cannot import my bookmarks, but as it will getting better, so I would use it when it can work well in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I turned to online bookmarks service, honestly pinboard is the best choice, but after it’s change to per-year price, it would be a little hard to accept that. Finally, I decide to use &lt;a href=&quot;https://delicious.com&quot;&gt;Delicious&lt;/a&gt;. It’s free but some ads there. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, a good app is needed for better experience, I use Shiori now, it’s light but beatiful, u can set the hot key to easily store and open the bookmarks.(like another Alfred, haha) &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://royxue.me/assets/img/blog/shiori.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hmmmm, I think maybe Im not going to import Chrome bookmarks into Delicous, but use Delicious as new service for storing bookmarks, Chrome bookmarks only for those website I always use in daily life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If u r interested, just follow &lt;a href=&quot;https://delicious.com/royxue&quot;&gt;me&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2015 11:29:01 +0900</pubDate>
        <link>http://royxue.me/blog/life/dev/bookmarks-migration-plan</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://royxue.me/blog/life/dev/bookmarks-migration-plan</guid>
        
        <category>bookmarks</category>
        
        <category>Mac OSX</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
        <category>life</category>
        
        <category>dev</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Dev: Start From Here</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The title is just a little bit weired, where is here? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to Kakazu San give my this oppotunity to do my own project in one month. This Monday, I shared my ideas in company meeting, and finally decide what to do in the following one month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The moment I decided the idea make me remind of 4 months ago in the Hackathon. Team always make things easier, but this time I can only do it by myself, which means building back end, front end, and design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it’s a good chance to try something cool! &lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2015 01:54:11 +0900</pubDate>
        <link>http://royxue.me/dev/start-from-here</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://royxue.me/dev/start-from-here</guid>
        
        <category>Japanese</category>
        
        <category>Rails</category>
        
        
        <category>dev</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Blog: Living in Japan</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Now it’s my third week in Japan. Life is just too busy to catch up all stuffs, like writing this blog :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whatever, I love this city, this country. Always I feel like that I am like a new delivered baby, so eager to see, to experience the this new world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I learnt Rails in previous 2 weeks, finished some web development tasks by Rails. I guess the actual time spending on learning Rails maybe less than one week? Im just not sure about it. But, Python and Ruby, Django and Rails are pretty similar except the grammar difference. The previous Django and Python knowledge helped me a lot on Ruby. Ruby is kind of language you can write like a poem, which means one beautiful line to do something powerful, hmmm, this is what I wanna learn more in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guest the most important things on my wish list have been finished, saw kojiharu in the real life is the best moment in Japan till now. It’s a little bit difficult to describe the feeling at that moment. doki doki doki doki. haha.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next week, I will start my own project, although till now I have no idea about what to do. Im looking forward to the first step, because there are lots of things to learn, to try, to enjoy!~~~&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2015 18:36:40 +0900</pubDate>
        <link>http://royxue.me/blog/life/living-in-japan</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://royxue.me/blog/life/living-in-japan</guid>
        
        <category>travel</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
        <category>life</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Project: Theano</title>
        <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;theano&quot;&gt;Theano&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Theano is a Python library that allows you to define, optimize, and evaluate mathematical expressions involving multi-dimensional arrays efficiently. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.deeplearning.net/software/theano&quot;&gt;http://www.deeplearning.net/software/theano&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2015 01:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
        <link>http://royxue.me/project/theano</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://royxue.me/project/theano</guid>
        
        <category>deep learning</category>
        
        
        <category>project</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Project: Alfred Workflows</title>
        <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;mouhttpsgithubcomroyxuealfredworkflowstreemastermou&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/royxue/Alfred_workflows/tree/master/Mou&quot;&gt;Mou&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mou is an Alfred Workflow by which you can use “moo” easily find .md files(only .md files show in search result) on your Mac and open it by Mou.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;macdownhttpsgithubcomroyxuealfredworkflowstreemastermacdown&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/royxue/Alfred_workflows/tree/master/Macdown&quot;&gt;Macdown&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Macdown is an Alfred Workflow by which you can use “mcc” easily find .md files(only .md files show in search result) on your Mac and open it by Macdown.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2015 08:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
        <link>http://royxue.me/project/alfred</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://royxue.me/project/alfred</guid>
        
        <category>alfred workflow</category>
        
        
        <category>project</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Blog: Chinese New Year</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;hmmmm，又是一年春节，果然只有这个节日对中国人来说才算是一年的始末。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;不知道自己究竟是抱着什么样的心情来过年的。能过年还是要感谢迟到的那份签证，虽然一开始不是这么打算的。不过，可能以后几年都没有办法回来过年了，想想还是挺好的。而且今年年三十晚上可以一家三口一起过啦，老妈没有排到三十的夜班还是蛮好的。大概我对过年的期待也就这些了。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;最近的事情依然很多，而且回家之后变得特别懒，工作效率直线下降。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;theano最近的进度，大体的功能已经完成，只是最近和Fred两个人在纠结一些细节上的东西。这段时间真的学到了很多有用的东西. 自己也越发明白开源的意义和成为开源贡献者的不易. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;开始准备rails，不过发现大概是前一段时间搞了django之后，中毒很深？觉得在看rails的时候，在一些地方思维模式一下子转不过来。总是想在rails里面找和django一样的实现方式。然而两者之间的区别还是蛮大的，估计从现在卡住的这几个坑里挣扎出来之后, 学习速度会快很多. (噗, 在断断续续写这个玩意儿的期间破解了一个坑了)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;还有就是手贱写了一下swift, 果然不会设计弄得太丑, 搞得兴致下降啊啊啊啊. 且行且珍惜吧.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;哦, 对了, 值得一提的是, 这个, 也算是体验了一次从天堂到地狱的心灵过山车, 觉得自己愈发强大了. 不过想想, 毕竟有6个小时的时间冒充了一下全球top9%的小伙伴的人生还是很不错的. hmmmmm, 事实证明我的第六感果然很通灵. 两眼都是泪, 不说了.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;新年愿望?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;hmmm, 戒掉拖延症.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;小嶋陽菜握手会!!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;还有就是拿到一个自己满意的offer啦~&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BTW: 最近都没写什么正经东西(根本就没写东西…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;所以最近要好好努力~&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2015 00:36:21 +0900</pubDate>
        <link>http://royxue.me/blog/life/chinese-new-year</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://royxue.me/blog/life/chinese-new-year</guid>
        
        <category>zh_cn</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
        <category>life</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Project: 鲜声</title>
        <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;section&quot;&gt;鲜声&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;鲜声聚合社交媒体上的爆点及热点内容，提供个性化订阅和及时推送服务，主题多样，是一个带有个性趣味的新鲜订阅平台。
Xiansheng is a light iOS app, a subscription platform with pushing service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;contribution&quot;&gt;Contribution&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Built server side during my internship at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ifanr.com/&quot;&gt;iFanr&lt;/a&gt;, mainly using Django.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2015 08:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
        <link>http://royxue.me/project/xiansheng</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://royxue.me/project/xiansheng</guid>
        
        <category>iOS, App</category>
        
        
        <category>project</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Blog: Thai Trip</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;回到家的第一件事就是连着睡了十几个小时的觉.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;本来是打算要去台湾, 结果因为时间来不及办理通行证只能临时更改目的地去泰国. 不知道这算不算是完成了2014年未完成的旅行心愿. 不过从学校回家的时候没有带那本Thailand Lonely Planet还是很遗憾. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;因为是要陪老妈一起去玩, 她又执意不愿意自由行, 无奈只能报旅游团. 不过还是选了一个有一天自由活动的团. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;泰国和想象中的有些不一样. 大概也是因为旅游团去的地方都是大景点, 放眼望去, 看不尽的中国人. 自由行的最后一天, 趁着曼谷大堵车, 和出租车司机聊了一下所谓的泰国旅游. 最悲哀的事情就是中国人出了国还要被自己的同胞坑, 说着一口普通话的华人/华裔导游其实并非是正规导游, 一般旅游团都会有两个导游, 一个中国人, 一个泰国人, 泰国人持有导游证, 负责卖票, 应付旅游警察, 全程不会说什么话. 中国导游只负责骗人, 告诉你所谓的皇家XX中心是国王开的. 青草药膏, 虎牌膏药, 各种动物皮包, 蛇药等等当地人根本不用, 泰国的土豪也是买奢侈品的. 所以说, 中国人的出国旅游简直就是一部交国际智商税的血泪史…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;hmmm, 说些好的, 泰国还是一个很不错的国家. 曼谷看起来很庄严, 大概是因为有很多政府机关, 和很多的寺庙. Siam Center大概是最繁华的中心, 难以想象的是在购物商场的楼下竟然有一个超级棒的水族馆, 五星推荐! 芭堤雅是个很不一样的城市, 大概也是因为太开放了, 在大街上就已经是男男女女分不清楚了, 也真的有很多欧美大叔来租妻. 到了晚上, 红灯区的街上, 沙滩上到处是拉客的, 漂亮的还不少是人妖…唯一遗憾的是没有来得及去看信不信由你博物馆.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;哎, 最写不动的就是游记了, 想说的东西太多, 可是要写下来的时候却懒得打字了. Whatever, memory is the most valuable thing :)&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2015 01:12:22 +0900</pubDate>
        <link>http://royxue.me/blog/explorer/thai-trip</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://royxue.me/blog/explorer/thai-trip</guid>
        
        <category>Thai</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
        <category>explorer</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
